<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

	<title>RobWeychert.com V7</title>
	<description>A work in progress</description>
	<link>https://v7.robweychert.com</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 11:27:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
	<pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 11:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
	
	<item>
		<title>Timeline section inventory</title>
		<description><![CDATA[
			<p>Progress on the redesign has slowed, partly because I’ve been busy with other things, and partly because, frankly, the open questions about the timeline section enumerated in my <a href="https://v7.robweychert.com/blog/2020/01/v7-structural-challenges/">previous post</a> are an intimidating mess, a perfect example of the early stages of the <a href="https://thedesignsquiggle.com/">Design Squiggle</a>.</p>

		<figure>
			<img src="/assets/images/2020-02-09-design-squiggle.svg">
			<figcaption><a href="https://thedesignsquiggle.com/">The Design Squiggle</a>, by Damien Newman</figcaption>
		</figure>

		<p>In a fight or flight situation like this, here are the arguments for flight:</p>

		<ul>
			<li>“Uh, the timeline isn’t even your <a href="https://v7.robweychert.com/blog/2020/01/v7-content-priorities/">top priority</a> for the site, remember? What’s more important: working on exciting projects and making it easy for people to find them, or laboring endlessly over a tortured accounting of years of less significant output?”</li>
			<li>“Isn’t this whole timeline thing just an exercise in narcissism anyway?”</li>
		</ul>

		<p>They’re fair points. I’ll need to be careful not to get so bogged down in the timeline’s minutia that it jeopardizes the timely rollout of the projects section, which is more important. It’s also worth considering whether the timeline is more of an <em>accumulation</em> than a <em>collection</em>. I think of something Yoko Ono <a href="https://twitter.com/yokoono/status/6801795928">said</a>:</p>

		<blockquote>
			<p>Unclog your mind. Unclog your room. Arrange your room in a way you wish your mind would be.</p>
		</blockquote>

		<p>In the physical world, I do periodic purges of inessential objects to keep things manageable and focused. However, I have a persistent belief that the timeline concept is more than the overwrought sum of its sprawling parts, something I’ve expressed <a href="https://v6.robweychert.com/blog/2017/10/ten-years-twitter/">before</a> with regard to Twitter:</p>

		<blockquote>
			<p>I’m more interested in Twitter as an <a href="https://v6.robweychert.com/blog/2017/09/v6-the-archive/">archive</a>, as a collection of bite-sized dispatches from events in our lives that run the gamut from mundane to sublime, which can be recombined in various ways to tell a uniquely affecting story.</p>
		</blockquote>

		<p>So for now I’ll choose fight over flight, and my first move is to take inventory of the timeline’s content sources and the various shapes they take. The only thing every timeline node has in common is a date. Otherwise, these are the categories I’ve settled on for the data in play:</p>

		<ul>
			<li>title</li>
			<li>description</li>
			<li>short text</li>
			<li>long text</li>
			<li>image</li>
			<li>video</li>
			<li>metadata (other than date)</li>
			<li>rating</li>
			<li>seriality (part of a series)</li>
		</ul>

		<p>Below are the content sources and how data categories map to them, in descending order of volume, as of February 9, 2020:</p>

		<table>
			<thead>
				<tr>
					<th>Content source</th>
					<th>Active?</th>
					<th>Entries</th>
					<th>Always includes</th>
					<th>Sometimes includes</th>
					<th>Notes</th>
				</tr>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<tr>
					<td><a href="https://twitter.com/robweychert">Twitter</a></td>
					<td>yes</td>
					<td>8,372</td>
					<td></td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>short text</li>
							<li>image(s)</li>
							<li>video</li>
							<li>seriality</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>Amount includes unknown number of retweets, which will be omitted</li>
							<li>Some primary content is cross-posted from other timeline sources</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td><a href="https://letterboxd.com/robweychert">Letterboxd</a></td>
					<td>yes</td>
					<td>1,225</td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>title</li>
							<li>metadata</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>short text</li>
							<li>long text</li>
							<li>rating</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>Metadata includes location, format, and more, in the form of unclassified tags</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/robweychert/">Flickr</a></td>
					<td>no</td>
					<td>1,188</td>
					<td></td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>title</li>
							<li>short text</li>
							<li>long text</li>
							<li>image</li>
							<li>video</li>
							<li>metadata</li>
							<li>seriality</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>Some primary content is cross-posted from other timeline sources</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td><a href="https://robweychert.com">RobWeychert.com</a></td>
					<td>yes</td>
					<td>543</td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>metadata</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>title</li>
							<li>description</li>
							<li>short text</li>
							<li>long text</li>
							<li>image(s)</li>
							<li>video(s)</li>
							<li>seriality</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>Metadata includes topic tags</li>
							<li>Some entries which V6 collects in digests (like <a href="https://v6.robweychert.com/blog/topic/daily-haiku/">Daily Haiku</a>) will be broken out into individual entries. Other entries (like <a href="https://v4.robweychert.com/consumption/">Consumption</a>) may have to remain digested because their original entry dates are lost.</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td><a href="https://tinnitus.robweychert.com">Tinnitus Tracker</a></td>
					<td>yes</td>
					<td>427</td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>title</li>
							<li>metadata</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>short text</li>
							<li>long text</li>
							<li>image(s)</li>
							<li>video(s)</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>Metadata includes classified tags: genre(s), artist(s), venue, city, state</li>
							<li>Some primary content is cross-posted from other timeline sources</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td><a href="https://instagram.com/therobweychert">Instagram</a></td>
					<td>yes</td>
					<td>184</td>
					<td></td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>short text</li>
							<li>image(s)</li>
							<li>video(s)</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>Some primary content is cross-posted from other timeline sources</li>
							<li>My previous Instagram account (2010–2012) was deleted but may be able to be reconstructed from cross-posts</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td><a href="https://dribbble.com/robweychert">Dribbble</a></td>
					<td>no</td>
					<td>42</td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>title</li>
							<li>image</li>
							<li>metadata</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>short text</li>
							<li>seriality</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>Metadata includes various unclassified tags</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
				</tr>
				<tr>
					<td><a href="https://v6.robweychert.com/blog/#browse-by-source">29 more miscellaneous sources</a></td>
					<td>mostly no</td>
					<td>106</td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>title</li>
							<li>metadata</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>description</li>
							<li>short text</li>
							<li>long text</li>
							<li>image(s)</li>
							<li>video(s)</li>
							<li>rating</li>
							<li>seriality</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
					<td>
						<ul>
							<li>Metadata includes topic tags</li>
						</ul>
					</td>
				</tr>
			</tbody>
		</table>

		<p>This inventory will hopefully help me work through the UX/UI implications of the timeline, which I’ll do next with some sketches and mockups.</p>

		<h3>Other updates</h3>

		<p>This post prompted me to add a little CSS to keep image sizes in check, as well as some simple table borders, because most browsers’ default table styles are not very useful:</p>

		<pre><code>img,
svg {
  display: block;
  max-width: 100%;
}

table,
th,
td {
  border: 1px solid black;
}</code></pre>

		<p>I also replaced the reverse-chronological “Most recent blog posts” at the bottom of each post with previous/next navigation, and took a page out of <a href="https://frankchimero.com/blog/2019/redesign/">Frank Chimero’s book</a> by making the <a href="/blog/">blog landing page</a> a chronological table of contents.</p>

		]]></description>
		<link>https://v7.robweychert.com/blog/2020/02/v7-timeline-section-inventory/</link>
		<guid>https://v7.robweychert.com/blog/2020/02/v7-timeline-section-inventory/</guid>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 11:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Structural challenges</title>
		<description><![CDATA[
			<p>Most of this redesign’s structural challenges pertain to the timeline section, <a href="https://v7.robweychert.com/blog/2020/01/v7-introduction/">previously described thusly</a>:</p>

		<blockquote>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Timeline:</strong> The blog on the current version of my site, V6, <a href="https://v6.robweychert.com/blog/">collects</a> most of what I’ve written for public consumption since 2001 across nearly 40 different sources. I’d like to expand that to include even more sources and content types, collecting virtually everything I’ve shared online in one sprawling, sortable/filterable timeline.</li>
			</ul>
		</blockquote>

		<p>Since the projects section is a <a href="https://v7.robweychert.com/blog/2020/01/v7-content-priorities/">higher priority</a> and the new parts of the timeline may not even be included in the site’s initial launch, it’s tempting to just put the timeline on the back burner. But here’s the thing: the timeline’s structural challenges will inevitably introduce technical challenges, which will have a big influence on what tools I use to build the site. I want to pick the right tools the first time, and I’ll give myself a better chance of doing that by working out the specifics of the timeline concept now and trying to wrangle it into a good user experience that’s technically feasible.</p>

		<p>However, I’m only willing to go to so much trouble to make the timeline a reality, so if it turns out that what I have in mind is too architecturally convoluted in terms of UX and/or execution, I’ll scale the concept back until I find the right compromise. But let’s start by thinking big.</p>

		<p>My V6 blog currently contains 544 posts from 39 sources. That 544 number is a bit misleading, because a number of those posts are digests of many smaller posts. For example, I used to publish a haiku every weekday, and rather than make each haiku an individual post, I collected them in <a href="https://v6.robweychert.com/blog/topic/daily-haiku/">monthly digests</a>. Similarly, film reviews I’ve written on Letterboxd that are fewer than 100 words are collected in annual “<a href="https://v6.robweychert.com/blog/2019/12/letterboxd-loose-ends/">loose ends</a>” posts. I did this mainly for two reasons:</p>

		<ol>
			<li>I wasn’t crazy about the idea of an entire webpage devoted to just a few words.</li>
			<li>It’s a static site made with Jekyll, which means more posts make for longer build times. (The site currently takes about 40 seconds to build, due to a variety of factors.)</li>
		</ol>

		<p>The former doesn’t bother me so much anymore, but it does introduce design challenges. The latter is emblematic of the technical challenges that may lie ahead, especially considering that I’m trying to add a <em>lot</em> more content. Here are the biggest troublemakers:</p>

		<ul>
			<li><a href="https://twitter.com/robweychert">Tweets</a> (more than 8,300)</li>
			<li><a href="https://letterboxd.com/robweychert/films/diary/">Letterboxd film diary entries</a> (more than 1,200)</li>
			<li><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/robweychert/">Flickr photos</a> (more than 1,200)</li>
			<li><a href="https://tinnitus.robweychert.com/">Tinnitus Tracker live music diary entries</a> (more than 400)</li>
		</ul>

		<p>Even if most of the content to be added is bite-sized, accounting for each of those bites is a big task: the number of individual posts on the site will grow more than 20 times. Compounding the technical complexity introduced by that sheer volume are issues of taxonomy and UI. Some of the many open questions:</p>

		<ul>
			<li>How to handle the information architecture and URL structure? I kind of like the idea of keeping everything under /blog/, since this is a log of things I’ve done on the web, but “blog” has more specific connotations now. Maybe the aggregate of posts can be browsed under /timeline/ and individual posts can be categorized à la /blog/, /notes/, /images/, etc?</li>
			<li>How to handle tweet replies and threads, especially ones that occur over extended time periods? Is there a good way to make a tweet an individual post but still acknowledge its context among other tweets, many of which are from other people?</li>
			<li>Given the issue of build times, can this still be a static site? I really like being able to build my site from a local directory of text files, without relying on server-side software that abstracts the content away into a database and requires remote maintenance. But is that still a viable option for a site this big? If I need to switch to another kind of CMS, how much of a lift will data migration be?</li>
			<li>For data sources that I’m still updating regularly, like Twitter and Letterboxd, can/should I syndicate them out from my site, presumably with the help of some <a href="https://indieweb.org/">IndieWeb</a> technology? Or download my data from those services periodically and backfill? Will I be able to integrate multiple collections of downloaded JSON data with my existing blog posts?</li>
			<li>How much metadata should I publish? On Letterboxd in particular, I have a fairly rich tagging system. Can/should I integrate that into my site? What relationship should it have with my site’s existing tag/topic system? Should incoming data without tags (like Twitter) somehow be retroactively tagged?</li>
			<li><strong>What the hell am I getting myself into??</strong></li>
		</ul>

		<p>Next up: sketches and research!</p>

		]]></description>
		<link>https://v7.robweychert.com/blog/2020/01/v7-structural-challenges/</link>
		<guid>https://v7.robweychert.com/blog/2020/01/v7-structural-challenges/</guid>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 09:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Content priorities</title>
		<description><![CDATA[
			<p>I added a tiny bit of CSS to aid readability by keeping line lengths in check on larger viewports:</p>

		<pre><code>body {
  margin: 0 auto;
  max-width: 75ch;
  padding: 1rem;
}</code></pre>

		<p>When calling the CSS file from the page <code>head</code>, I include a query string based on today’s date, which I’ll update when the CSS is updated. This will let updates get past the browser’s cache.</p>

		<pre><code>&lt;link rel="stylesheet" href="/assets/css/main.css?20200108"&gt;</code></pre>

		<p>Hopefully this small stylistic addition will keep things tidy enough until I properly begin the visual part of the design process. Before I can get to that, though, let’s talk content priorities. From my list of reasons for the V7 redesign in its <a href="https://v7.robweychert.com/blog/v7-introduction/">introductory post</a>:</p>

		<blockquote>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Timeline:</strong> The blog on the current version of my site, V6, <a href="https://v6.robweychert.com/blog/">collects</a> most of what I’ve written for public consumption since 2001 across nearly 40 different sources. I’d like to expand that to include even more sources and content types, collecting virtually everything I’ve shared online in one sprawling, sortable/filterable timeline.</li>
				<li><strong>Projects:</strong> I’ve made a lot of cool things personally and professionally over the past few years, announced their launches, and written about why and how they were made, but I still need an easily browsable place to collect and share that work.</li>
			</ul>
		</blockquote>

		<p>The timeline is listed first because it’s the more complex of the two, but projects are actually a higher priority.</p>

		<p>As noted above, a version of the timeline already exists in V6, and while I want to rethink its structure a bit for V7, most of its substance is already in place. Whatever additions are made can be made post-launch if necessary. In the meantime, most of those additions (e.g. tweets and Flickr photos) are for now easily found and browsed elsewhere online, so their inclusion isn’t all that urgent.</p>

		<p>Projects, on the other hand, are currently Easter eggs at best. They’re out there, and you might be able to find them if you’re looking for them, but you’re unlikely to stumble upon them, and they can’t be seen in aggregate as a body of work. Compared to the timeline additions, most of which are old and vary widely in terms of value and substance, the projects’ inclusion is a high priority, because they’re recent and substantial and they represent how I’m spending a lot of my time, so I want them to be much more visible.</p>

		<p>So those are my high-level content priorities for V7. Almost the entirety of the site’s content will fall within one of these two areas, so their structure is the site’s structure. In the next post, I’ll get into my ideas for that structure and the challenges they present.</p>

		]]></description>
		<link>https://v7.robweychert.com/blog/2020/01/v7-content-priorities/</link>
		<guid>https://v7.robweychert.com/blog/2020/01/v7-content-priorities/</guid>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 08:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>The “viewport” meta tag</title>
		<description><![CDATA[
			<p>The first thing I did when setting up this new version of my site was to put together some minimum viable HTML templates. Here’s the blog post template:</p>

		<pre><code>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html lang="en"&gt;

&lt;head&gt;
  &lt;meta charset="utf-8"&gt;
  &lt;title&gt;&lt;!--POST TITLE--&gt; | RobWeychert.com V7&lt;/title&gt;
  &lt;meta name="description" content="&lt;!--POST DESCRIPTION--&gt;"&gt;
  &lt;link rel="alternate" type="application/rss+xml" title="RobWeychert.com V7" href="/index.rss"&gt;
&lt;/head&gt;

&lt;body&gt;

  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href="/"&gt;RobWeychert.com V7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;nav&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/blog/"&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/index.rss"&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/nav&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;

  &lt;aside&gt;I’m redesigning my site in public from the ground up, so if it looks undercooked, that’s why! Check out the &lt;a href="/blog/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; to follow the process step by step, or visit the more polished &lt;a href="https://v6.robweychert.com/"&gt;current version&lt;/a&gt; of the site.&lt;/aside&gt;

  &lt;main&gt;
    &lt;header&gt;
      &lt;h2&gt;&lt;!--POST TITLE--&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;!--POST DESCRIPTION--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;time datetime="&lt;!--YYYY-MM-DD--&gt;"&gt;&lt;!--POST DATE--&gt;&lt;/time&gt;
    &lt;/header&gt;

    &lt;!--POST CONTENT--&gt;

  &lt;/main&gt;

  &lt;nav aria-label="Secondary"&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Most recent blog posts&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;a href="/blog/&lt;!--YYYY/MM/POST TITLE SLUG--&gt;/"&gt;
          &lt;h3&gt;&lt;!--POST TITLE--&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;!--POST DESCRIPTION--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;time datetime="&lt;!--YYYY-MM-DD--&gt;"&gt;&lt;!--POST DATE--&gt;&lt;/time&gt;
        &lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/nav&gt;

&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;</code></pre>

	<p>The site is, for the time being, made exclusively of HTML, so I didn’t bother to test it on different devices since browsers would apply their own default styles. But then I noticed it was doing this on iOS:</p>

	<figure>
		<img src="/assets/images/2020-01-04-ios-shrunken.png" width="300" alt="Screenshot of a shrunken blog post in iOS Firefox">
		<figcaption>iOS shrinks the page, treating it as if it were designed specifically for desktop browsers.</figcaption>
	</figure>

	<p>It turned out my minimum viable HTML wasn’t quite viable after all! I had left out the <code>&lt;meta name="viewport"&gt;</code> tag from the <code>&lt;head&gt;</code>. It’s been part of my HTML boilerplate for years, and I’ve always generally understood what it does, but this incident prompted me to learn a little more. After digging around a bit, I found an in-depth <a href="https://www.quirksmode.org/mobile/viewports.html">two</a>-<a href="https://www.quirksmode.org/mobile/viewports2.html">part</a> post from Peter-Paul Koch on how browser viewports work with device pixels and CSS pixels. I also found Apple’s <a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/archive/documentation/AppleApplications/Reference/SafariWebContent/UsingtheViewport/UsingtheViewport.html">documentation</a> for configuring the viewport using <code>&lt;meta name="viewport"&gt;</code>. Both of those posts appear to have been published around 2010, but much of the information is still relevant.</p>

	<p>Due to the complexity of the subject, those posts are illuminating if not quite elucidating, but here’s the gist: When the iPhone was first released, Apple proudly trumpeted its ability to bring mobile users the “real” internet: not the stripped down mobile versions of websites that were de rigeur at the time (on the rare occasions developers even bothered making them), but the “real” versions that you would see on a desktop computer. It rendered these desktop-optimized sites by assuming they were approximately 980 pixels wide and shrinking everything to fit on the iPhone’s screen, which was 320 pixels wide. The user could then zoom and pan the page to get a closer look. This was a reasonable compromise, but it meant that if anyone tried to optimize a site’s design for a mobile device, that page would likewise be shrunken when rendered on the iPhone. So Apple created the <code>&lt;meta name="viewport"&gt;</code> tag, which would give developers control over how their work was rendered on the iPhone. Other mobile browser makers subsequently adopted it, making it a <a href="https://drafts.csswg.org/css-device-adapt/#viewport-meta">de facto standard</a>.</p>

	<p>Fast-forward more than a decade and no one thinks of the desktop as the default way to experience the web anymore, so I thought I might be able to get away with omitting <code>&lt;meta name="viewport"&gt;</code>. Apparently not! Maybe someday. In the meantime, you can see the aforementioned Apple <a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/archive/documentation/AppleApplications/Reference/SafariWebContent/UsingtheViewport/UsingtheViewport.html">documentation</a> for details on how to use <code>&lt;meta name="viewport"&gt;</code>, but this should cover you in most cases:</p>

	<pre><code>&lt;meta name="viewport" content="width=device-width, initial-scale=1"&gt;</code></pre>

	<figure>
		<img src="/assets/images/2020-01-04-ios-correct.png" width="300" alt="Screenshot of a correctly rendered blog post in iOS Firefox">
		<figcaption>No more shrinkage!</figcaption>
	</figure>

		]]></description>
		<link>https://v7.robweychert.com/blog/2020/01/v7-viewport-meta-tag/</link>
		<guid>https://v7.robweychert.com/blog/2020/01/v7-viewport-meta-tag/</guid>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Introduction</title>
		<description><![CDATA[
			<p>Welcome to RobWeychert.com V7! There are a number of new things I want to try with my site, from structure to aesthetics to code, and so it’s time to begin a fresh redesign. Inspired by my friends <a href="https://2020.destroytoday.com/">Jonnie</a> and <a href="https://redesign.frankchimero.com/">Frank</a>, I’ve decided to do it in public from the ground up. I’m starting with bare-bones HTML and as the design process unfolds, each step will be reflected on the site in real time and documented with a succinct blog post. I’m hoping to post at least once a week, but that will probably fluctuate.</p>

		<p>Here are some of the core ideas driving the redesign, which I’ll flesh out further in subsequent posts:</p>

		<ul>
			<li><strong>Timeline:</strong> The blog on the current version of my site, V6, <a href="https://v6.robweychert.com/blog/">collects</a> most of what I’ve written for public consumption since 2001 across nearly 40 different sources. I’d like to expand that to include even more sources and content types, collecting virtually everything I’ve shared online in one sprawling, sortable/filterable timeline.</li>
			<li><strong>Projects:</strong> I’ve made a lot of cool things personally and professionally over the past few years, announced their launches, and written about why and how they were made, but I still need an easily browsable place to collect and share that work.</li>
			<li><strong>Overprint:</strong> The basis of the aesthetic I want to explore.</li>
			<li><strong>Tools and tech:</strong> My approach to layout and style is evolving with the help of expanding browser support for CSS specs like Flexbox, Grid, and Custom Properties. I’m also considering moving away from Jekyll to another static site generator as well as updating my deployment method from FTP sync to something more modern.</li>
		</ul>

		<p>More to come. Stay tuned!</p>

		]]></description>
		<link>https://v7.robweychert.com/blog/2020/01/v7-introduction/</link>
		<guid>https://v7.robweychert.com/blog/2020/01/v7-introduction/</guid>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
	</item>
	
</channel>
</rss>